RON GRUESBECK

Software Engineer

I'm a software engineer specializing in all things JavaScript. I discovered software while working in the wine industry where I built an ethanol prediction model. Shortly after, I left wine to chase my dream of being a musician and continued exploring software development by co-founding a design and tech agency.

WORK EXPERIENCE

GOMETA, INC

Software Developer | Apr, 2019 - Current

NIXIE AGENCY

Co-Founder | Aug, 2014 - Mar, 2019

Technical projects: - Scientific simulation interface with Python + Qt/PySide - Event ticket sales with admin interface and REST API backend - React/Redux client with Go JSON REST API - Interactive indoor map UI with SVG and Snap.svg - Ruby on Rails app with Postgres DB on Heroku Client list: City of Napa, Di Rosa, Jubilee USA Network, Napa Valley Arts Council, Napa Valley Museum, Seva Foundation, ZD Wines.

TRICHERO FAMILY ESTATES

Senior Lab Tech | Aug, 2010 – Jul, 2013

- General wine analysis for Trinchero Family Estates - Automated recheck heuristics for enzymatic analysis with visual basic - Built a prediction model for ethanol and methanol concentrations using infrared data, Python, and R

EDUCATION

PACIFIC UNION COLLEGE

BSc - Biology

PROJECTS

GITHUB.COM/RGRUESBECK/PROJECTS



JavaScript Linux

CONTACT INFORMATION

Email: ron@rongruesbeck.com

Website: https://rgruesbeck.github.io/about/